Up until now, we've discussed four data types in Python: Int,
到目前为止 我们已经讨论了 Python 中的四种数据类型
float, bool, and string.
整型 浮点型 布尔型和字符串
If you recall from our previous video,
在上个视频中我提到
you can check the type of any object directly using the built-in function type.
你可以使用内置函数 type() 直接查看任何对象的类型
Using type, we can observe that the same number can be coded in different types,
通过 type() 我们可以发现同一数字可以表示成不同的类型
each with their own set of behaviors.
每种类型都有自己的一组行为
As a side note, here,
顺便提一下
we're calling a function print on the output of another function type.
这里 我们对另一个函数 type() 的输出调用函数 print()
We use parenthesis to define the order in which functions get run.
我们使用括号来定义函数的运行顺序
What's contained in one set of parenthesis needs to be
需要先评估一组括号里的函数
evaluated first before being given as input to the next function.
然后再作为另一个函数的输入
Here, the type function is run first and then its output is printed.
这里 首先运行 type 函数 然后输出它的结果
Different types have different properties.
不同的类型具有不同的属性
And when you're designing on computer program,
在设计计算机程序时
you'll need to choose the types for your data based on how you're going to use them.
你需要根据如何使用数据来为属性选择一种类型
For example, if you want to use a number as a part of a sentence,
例如 如果你想在句子中使用某个数字
it'll be easiest if that number is a string.
则最简单的方法是将该数字设为字符串
If you want to encode a true-false value,
如果你想表示 true 或 false 值
it'll be much easier to manipulate as a boolean than a string.
则用布尔型（而不是字符串）会简单很多
Why is it easier?
为何更简单呢？
There are specially designed functions for working with each data type.
每种数据类型都有专门的函数
You'll learn about these soon.
很快你将学习这些函数
You might also have situations where you don't control the type of data that you receive,
有时候 你无法控制所接收的数据的类型
but you still need to use it.
虽然依然需要使用它
The good news is that you can create
好消息是 你可以使用旧对象创建新的对象
new objects from old and change a type in the process.
并在创建过程中更改类型
We went over this in the integers and floats video.
我们在整型和浮点型视频中讲过这方面的知识
For example, here, we create an int from a float and assign it to a variable count.
例如 这里我们用浮点型创建了一个整型 并赋值给变量 count
Here, we create a string out of
这里 我们使用 house_number 创建了一个字符串
the house_number and use that to build a larger address string.
并用它来构建一个更大的 address 字符串
First, we have the house_number,
首先是 house_number
as well as the street and town_name.
然后是 street_name 和 town_name
You can see that the house_number is currently an int.
可以看出 house_number 目前是整型
We can change it to a string, like this,
我们可以像这样将其更改为字符串
and use the plus operator to create the full address.
并使用加号创建完整的地址
You can also build a number from a string like this.
还可以像这样使用字符串构建数字
Here, we start with a string of 35.
我们以字符串 35 开始
But by wrapping it in a float function,
但是通过将其放入 float() 函数中
we can see the type has now changed.
可以看出现在类型发生了变化